[
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Tanzania?",
        "answer": "Dodoma"
    },
    {
        "question": "Dodoma is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "Tanzania"
    },
    {
        "question": "Dodoma is the capital of which African country?",
        "answer": "Tanzania"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where was the first climate-controlled indoor mall in the U.S.?",
        "answer": "Edina, Minnesota - The Southdale Center opened in the Minneapolis suburb of Edina in 1956. It featured two floors with 72 stores."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the oldest bridge across Venice`s Grand Canal?",
        "answer": "Rialto Bridge -- Built by architect-engineer Antonio da Ponte and his nephew, the bridge is supported by 6,000 timber piles."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which American city is considered to be the birthplace of blues music?",
        "answer": "Memphis, Tennessee -- In 1977, the U.S. Congress declared Beale Street to be the official `Home of the Blues`."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which city in the contiguous U.S. will lead you to Canada if you drive due south?",
        "answer": "Detroit -- From Detroit, drive south over the Ambassador Bridge across the Detroit River, and you`ll hit Windsor, Ontario."
    },
    {
        "question": "What U.S. state is the smallest by land area?",
        "answer": "Rhode Island -- At 1214 sq.mi., it is half the size of Miami-Dade County, FL (2431 sq. mi), but has nearly 400 miles of shoreline."
    },
    {
        "question": "What country`s Indigenous name translates to `Land of the Long White Cloud`?",
        "answer": "New Zealand -- In the 1200s, Maori settlers called the North Island `Aotearoa`, which translates to `long white cloud`."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the second largest country in the World?",
        "answer": "Canada"
    },
    {
        "question": "What Russian city boasts the Hermitage Museum?",
        "answer": "St. Petersburg"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is colder, the North or South Pole?",
        "answer": "The South Pole"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the largest city in Alaska?",
        "answer": "Anchorage"
    },
    {
        "question": "What tropic passes through Australia?",
        "answer": "The Tropic of Capricorn"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the only US state that borders a Canadian territory?",
        "answer": "Alaska"
    },
    {
        "question": "What US state`s southern border is marked by the original Mason Dixon Line?",
        "answer": "Pennsylvania"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what mountains is Camp David?",
        "answer": "Appalachian Mountains"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Grand Coulee Dam was built on what river?",
        "answer": "Columbia River"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the Hawaiian Islands is nicknamed the `Garden Isle`?",
        "answer": "Kauai"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the residents of the US state of New Hampshire called?",
        "answer": "New Hampshirites"
    },
    {
        "question": "The financial district of Wall Street is located in what city?",
        "answer": "New York"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Virginia`s state motto?",
        "answer": "Sic Semper Tyrannis"
    },
    {
        "question": "What state is also known as the Volunteer State?",
        "answer": "Tennessee"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Iguazu Falls lie on the border of Brazil and which country?",
        "answer": "Argentina"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which U.S. National Park is the colorful Grand Prismatic Spring?",
        "answer": "Yellowstone"
    },
    {
        "question": "What luxury fashion house funded the restoration of Rome`s Trevi Fountain?",
        "answer": "Fendi"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the most-popular meat served on Christmas in the United Kingdom?",
        "answer": "Turkey meat"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country observes an official Vernal Equinox Day?",
        "answer": "Japan"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Valentine`s Day referred to as in Finland?",
        "answer": "`Friend`s Day`"
    },
    {
        "question": "`Ital` is the word used to describe the cuisine of which group of people?",
        "answer": "Rastafarians"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the official State fruit of New York?",
        "answer": "Apple"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country is nicknamed `the land of a thousand lakes`?",
        "answer": "Finland"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the world`s largest university by enrollment?",
        "answer": "India"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many Smithsonian museums and galleries are in Washington, D.C.?",
        "answer": "17"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is King Tut`s tomb?",
        "answer": "Valley of the Kings"
    },
    {
        "question": "What three countries border Luxembourg?",
        "answer": "France, Germany, and Belgium"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are Easter Island`s famous statues called?",
        "answer": "Moai"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many US states does the Appalachian Trail run through?",
        "answer": "14"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which U.S. state has zero natural lakes?",
        "answer": "Maryland"
    },
    {
        "question": "Zion National Park is located in which U.S. state?",
        "answer": "Utah -- Zion National Park is a southwest Utah nature preserve distinguished by Zion Canyon`s steep red cliffs."
    },
    {
        "question": "Mt. Everest climber Sir Edmund Hillary was from what country?",
        "answer": "New Zealand"
    },
    {
        "question": "What continent can one find the pudu, the world`s smallest deer?",
        "answer": "South America"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which city is the world`s largest film studio?",
        "answer": "Hyderabad, India -- Covering 1,666 acres, the Ramoji Film City in Hyderabad is the largest film studio in the word."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the New England states is the largest in size?",
        "answer": "Maine"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of the US state of Iowa?",
        "answer": "Des Moines"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Shenandoah Valley is located in which US state?",
        "answer": "Virginia"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state`s name is derived from the Spanish words for `mountainous`?",
        "answer": "Montana"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which present day US state did Ponce De Leon explore?",
        "answer": "Florida"
    },
    {
        "question": "What river defines the southern border of Oklahoma?",
        "answer": "Red River"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many US states begin with the letter `O`?",
        "answer": "Three - Ohio, Oklahoma, and Oregon"
    }
]